Iheagwara Augustine

FULL STACK DEVELOPER/DATA SCIENTIST

Email | github | Linkedin | Medium | +36703016866

SUMMARY

Passionate Software Developer keen on tany Full Stack Developer or Data role. Excels in both front-end and back-end development, with specializations in JavaScript, Ruby, C, React and React Native. Known for rapid assimilation of new languages and technologies and also thriving in remote team collaborations.

PORTFOLIO

You can have a look at my portfolio page <u>portfolio</u> to check out some of my projects Edit: (THIS SITE IS UNDERGOING SOME CHANGES AND DUE TO PERSONAL ENGAGEMENTS SOME IN-PAGE LINKS MIGHT BE FAULTY I'LL SORT THIS OUT AS SOON AS POSSIBLE)

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, C, TypeScript, SQL, No-sql, python

Technologies: React.js, Vue.js, React Native, Node.js, Next.js, TailwindCss, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, nextjs, Python

Testing software: jest, lighthouse, github actions, Rspec

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Aws, Docker, REST, IDE's, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Communication and problem solving.

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Development & Mentor

October 2022 - Present

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack and Mobile development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building 30+projects both independently and via pair-programming.

DOCTORS APPOINTMENT APP — A fullstack app developed by a collaborative team which allows a user to book an appointment under a doctor depending on the doctors schedule Built with: (React-Redux, CSS, Ruby on Rails, Devise, Postgresql) **Developed**Link: projectlink

Chat-APP— A full-stack chat app built to show the effect of websockets and how they allow chatting in real tme possible

Built with: (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, TailwindCSS) *Developed*

Github: projecctlink

Airbnb Clone -

. This clone will offer similar functions to the popular rental platform, providing a seamless experience for users to list, search, and book rental properties. The project will focus on delivering a responsive and scalable application(Next, zustand, prisma) project link.

Movie App — A full-stack app that displays movies you can watch online and the details about them via an API (built with a partner)

Built with: (Ruby on Rail, CSS, SQL) **Developed**

link: project link

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) April 2023 – Present

Mentored two junior web developers per week, providing technical support through code

- Suggested code organization enhancements for a 100% boost in code quality and performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

February 2023 – November 2023

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.
- Now Working on some Data science related projects to be included here when theyre ready, if youre seeing and youre wondering if i data aligned the answer is YES!!!!!! .

Eotvos Lorand University

Computer science September 2023

• Relevant Coursework: Calculus,Imperative Programming, Python, Computer systems